Guide to the Czesław Miłosz Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Czesław Miłosz papers
1880-2000
1940-1989
GEN MSS 661
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
102.42
(261 boxes) + 2 broadside folders
The Czesław Miłosz Papers document the life and work of the poet, essayist and Nobel Laureate Czesław Miłosz. The papers consist of writings, correspondence, photographs, personal papers, audio material, and printed material (including newspaper clippings, printed ephemera and clandestine samizdat publications), spanning the years 1880-2000, with the bulk of the material dating from 1940 to 1989. While some writings, photographs and personal documents pre-date the Second World War, the earliest correspondence dates from 1946.
Miłosz, Czesław, 1911-2004
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The bulk of the papers were purchased from George Minkoff, 1987 and 1990 and Serendipity Books, 2001. Additional material was acquired by gift from Czesław Miłosz, 1966 and from Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1995-1997.
Conditions Governing Access
Correspondence with Jeanne Hersch, Jadwiga Tomaszewicz and Lillian Valee was formerly restricted until 2010. Five notebooks were formerly restricted until 2010. Correspondence with Józef Sadzik is restricted during the lifetime of John Peter Miłosz.
Boxes 254, 256-261: ‡a Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 255 (computer disk): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 162 (sound recordings): Restricted Fragile Material. Consult Access Services for further information.
Existence and Location of Copies
Portions of the collection are available on microfilm.
Associated Materials
Printed material received with the collection was removed for separate cataloging and can be accessed by searching the library's online catalog.
Czesław Miłosz, 1911-2004
Czesław Miłosz, poet, essayist and Nobel Laureate, was born on June 30, 1911 in Šeteniai (Szetejnie), Lithuania and died on August 14, 2004 in Kraków, Poland, at the age of 93. He married Janina Dłuska (1909-1986) in 1944 and they had two sons: Anthony and John Peter. His second wife Carol Thigpen, whom he married in 1992, died in 2002.
Miłosz grew up in Lithuania amid diverse languages and ethnicities (including Polish, Lithuanian, Russian and Jewish) yet retained a strong attachment to his native country and language throughout his decades of life in Western Europe and the United States. As a child and young adult, Miłosz lived under an unstable series of governments and regimes, witnessing the political and social upheavals of the two world wars and rise of the Eastern Bloc. Miłosz studied law at Stefan Batory University in Vilnius (also known as Vilnius University). It was during this time that he published his first poetry in the University publication Alma Mater Vilnensis (1930), and later in a slim printed collection Poemat o czasie zastygłym (1933). He also co-founded the literary group and journal Żagary in Vilnius. While traveling to Paris in the 1930s he met a distant relative, Oscar V. de Lubicz Milosz, who was to be an important lifelong influence.
After completing his studies Miłosz worked in radio, first for Polish Radio in Vilnius (1936-1937). His second collection of poems Trzy zimy (1936) was published during this time. When he was dismissed, apparently for political reasons (perhaps because he included Jewish authors in his literary programming), he moved to Warsaw and worked for Polish National Radio until the outbreak of the Second World War.
During the war, Miłosz produced several clandestine publications including the anthology Pieśń niepodległa ( Invincible song ) and the collection of his poems Wiersze ( Poems, under the pseudonym Jan Syruć). His war-time poems are ironically juxtaposed to the profound trauma of the war and the Nazi occupation of Warsaw. In Świat ( The World ) Miłosz created defiantly serene portraits of faith, hope, love, fear and recovery that are nevertheless testament to the heaviness of war (and in stark contrast to his earlier poems written in Vilnius). This and other poetry from 1936-1945 is collected in Ocalenie ( Rescue [1945]).
After the Second World War, Miłosz became a cultural attaché for the People's Republic of Poland in New York and Washington, D.C. He then accepted a post in France in 1950. Increasingly estranged from the Polish government, he defected in 1951, obtaining political asylum in France. His defection prompted criticism from leftist intellectuals (Pablo Neruda was among his outspoken critics). As Miłosz struggled with his exile and his role as a Polish-language poet in France, he published his analyses of contemporary political upheaval in numerous prose works and regular contributions to Kultura, the Polish-language literary monthly published in Paris. His first post-emigration volume of poems, Światło dzienne, was published by Institut Literacki in 1953. In Poland, his work was circulated chiefly in clandestine copies between 1951 and 1980 since his writing was censored.
Much of Miłosz's prose writing in the 1950s was semi-autobiographical. His early life in rural Lithuania inspired the characters in the novel Dolina Issy ( The valley of Issa, 1955). Zniewolony umysł ( The captive mind, 1953) and Zdobycie władzy ( The seizure of power, 1955), which thrust him into the international spotlight, examined the moral and psychological pressures of life under a repressive totalitarian regime, providing context for his decision to defect. Rodzinna europa ( Native realm, 1959) explores the difficulties of balancing his Eastern European identity and strong attachment to the Polish language with his life as an émigré.
Miłosz emigrated to the United States in 1960. He initially accepted a temporary lectureship at the University of California, Berkeley and was appointed Professor of Slavic Languages and Literatures in 1961. He maintained close ties with the Polish émigré community in Paris, visiting frequently and continuing his association with Instytut Literacki. His works of literary criticism and anthologies of Polish poetry published in the 1960s (including Postwar Polish poetry [1965] and History of Polish literature [1969]) drew increasing attention to Polish literature in Europe and the United States.
In the United States, Miłosz was confronted with the fact that Polish literature was little-known in American circles, referring to himself as "Wrong Honorable Professor Milosz/Who wrote poems in some unheard-of tongue" ( Magic Mountain [1975]). Any trace of self-conceived obscurity vanished in 1980 when he won the Nobel Prize for Literature. The decision to award Miłosz the prize was made just before the democratic Solidarity labor strikes in Poland became widespread (activity that led to the imposition of martial law in Poland and eventually to the democratic change of government in 1989). These events, together with the appointment of Pope John Paul II two years prior, constituted a dynamic affirmation of Polish culture in the world spotlight.
In 1981, Miłosz visited Poland for the first time since his defection thirty years earlier. He was welcomed by immense crowds who celebrated his writing and his recognition as Nobel Laureate. He met with numerous literary and political figures, including Lech Wałęsa (leader of the Solidarity movement and future President of the Republic of Poland).
Miłosz continued to travel extensively after his retirement from teaching in 1978, accepting appointments as a visiting lecturer from, among others, Harvard University and the University of Michigan. He traveled to Poland regularly and his visits were increasingly lengthy until he moved to Kraków in 2000. He continued to publish numerous volumes of poetry and prose works, including translations of his own poetry into English.
Miłosz was a prolific translator to and from Polish and his translations introduced many modern Polish poets (including Aleksander Wat and Anna Świrszczyńska) to English-language readers. He undertook the monumental task of translating portions of the Bible after studying the fifteenth-century Puławski Psalter. His English translations of Polish poetry are are compiled in anthologies such as Czas niepokoju (1958) and Mowa wiązana (1986).
Miłosz received numerous prizes and honors, including the Prix Littéraire Européen (1953), the Neustadt International Prize for Literature (1978), the Nobel Prize for Literature (1980), and a National Medal of Arts (1990). Additional information on Czesław Miłosz is available in standard print and online biographical resources.
Scope and Contents
The Czesław Miłosz Papers document the life and work of the poet, essayist and Nobel Laureate Czesław Miłosz. The papers consist of writings, correspondence, photographs, personal papers, audio material, and printed material (including newspaper clippings, printed ephemera and clandestine samizdat publications), spanning the years 1880-2000, with the bulk of the material dating from 1940 to 1989. While some writings, photographs and personal documents pre-date the Second World War, the earliest correspondence dates from 1946.
The papers document all aspects of Miłosz's professional life and include original holograph and typescript drafts of his major works of poetry and prose from 1945 to1992, drafts or transcripts of hundreds of essays, speeches and lectures, transcripts of radio broadcasts, teaching material, and documentation of his collaboration with Aleksander Wat.
The papers document the domains of Miłosz's eminent career as a poet, writer and scholar of Slavic literature, his creative writing process, the relation of literary figures to historical events and movements of the twentieth century (including the Second World War, the rise of Soviet-influenced Communist rule in Poland, and upheavals in the Polish government in the 1980s), and themes of exile and emigration, particularly as they relate to Polish émigrés in France and the United States. Correspondence and writings directly address the intellectual and political themes that are prevalent in Miłosz's work, such as the incompatibility of totalitarian government and creative expression, the nature of religious faith, and the pain of exile.
Miłosz maintained long-standing association with the Polish émigré community of Paris after he moved to the United States. He frequently corresponded with the affiliates of Institut Literacki. This relationship is also evident in his regular contributions to the monthly serial Kultura. Major correspondents in the papers include Józef Czapski, Jerzy Giedroyc, Jan Goślicki, Zbigniew Herbert, Zygmunt Hertz, Zofia Hertz, Konstanty Jeleński, Aleksander Wat and Paulina Wat.
In addition to Miłosz's writings, lectures and teaching, the papers include sporadic documentation of personal and financial matters. This documentation includes financial records, legal records (especially relating to immigration) and family photographs. Among the printed material that Miłosz collected are many clandestine (samizdat) publications that were produced in Poland despite prohibitive censorship. This collection, while fragmentary, is representative of clandestine publication activity during the 1980s.
Arrangement
Organized into nine series: I. Correspondence, 1946-2000. II. Writings. 1934-2000. III. Interviews, Lectures, Broadcasts and Readings, 1946-1990. IV. Aleksander Wat Memoir and Translations, 1963-1991. V. Professional Papers, 1960-1993. VI. Personal Papers, 1937-1995. VII. Photographs, circa 1880-1989. VIII. Writings of Others, 1928-1998. IX. Printed Material, 1929-1999.
Authors, Polish -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, Polish -- 20th Century; American literature -- 20th Century; Polish literature -- 20th Century; Polish poetry -- 20th Century; Poetry -- Translations into Polish; Poetry -- Translations into English; Poland -- History -- 1945-1980; Poland -- Intellectual life -- 1918-1945; Poland -- Intellectual life -- 1945-1989; Emigration and immigration; Nobel Prize winners; Born digital; Audiovisual materials; Audiotapes; Clippings (information artifacts); Notebooks; Photographs; Underground literature -- Poland; Authors; Poets; Translators; Błoński, Jan, 1931-; Czapski, Józef, 1896-1993; Giedroyc, Jerzy, 1906-2000; Goślicki, Jan; Herbert, Zbigniew, 1924-1998; Hersch, Jeanne, 1910-2000; Hertz, Zygmunt, 1908-1979; Hertz, Zofia; Jameson, Storm, 1891-1986; Jeleński, Konstanty A. (Konstanty Aleksander), 1922-1987; Międzyrzecki, Artur, 1922-1996; Miłosz, Andrzej; Miłosz, Czesław, 1911-2004; Miłosz, Janina; Milosz, O. V. de L. (Oscar Vladislas de Lubicz), 1877-1939; Sadzik, Józef; Stempowski, Jerzy, 1894-1969; Szymborska, Wisława, 1923-2012; Świrszczyńska, Anna, 1909-1984; Tomaszewicz, Jadwiga; Vallee, Lillian; Vincenz, Stanisław, 1888-1971; Wat, Aleksander, 1900-1967; Watowa, Ola, 1903-1991; Instytut Literacki (Paris, France); Wydawnictwo Literackie; Żagary (Writers' group)
- Correspondence, 1946-2000; Series I; 32.11; (78 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into three subseries: Postwar Correspondence, General Correspondence, and Special Congratulatory Letters and Telegrams.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists chiefly of Miłosz's incoming correspondence from writers, scholars, publishers, friends, family and fans. The earliest correspondence (filed in the separate subseries Postwar Correspondence) dates from the time period directly after the Second World War when Miłosz worked in diplomatic posts for the People's Republic of Poland in New York and in Washington, D.C. The latest correspondence is from 2000, when Miłosz moved to Kraków, where he spent the last four years of his life.
  The general correspondence details Miłosz's life and professional activity from his years in France in the 1950s through the year 2000. Topics of correspondence include practical business (e.g. publication agreements and travel for appearances), political matters (e.g. the plight of suppressed writers and artists in Poland), personal reflections, and literary and philosophical inquiry.
  Some files include drafts or copies of outgoing letters, as noted in folder descriptions.
  - Postwar Correspondence
    Arranged alphabetically.
    Related Archival Materials note
    Additional letters from many correspondents included in this subseries are filed in General Correspondence
    The subseries Postwar Correspondence consists of interfiled letters from two categories designated by Miłosz: "Letters, family and friends up to 1950" and "Letters, writers and artists up to 1950." The library's decision to retain this subseries as a distinct group reflects a distinction that made between this early correspondence and other, later correspondence. The time period of 1946-1950 was particularly challenging as his diplomatic service to the Polish government weighed heavily upon him. The subseries documents the early development of his criticisms of Eastern European communism that were later expressed in writings such as Zdobycie władzy and Zniewolony umysł.
    Some of this correspondence was printed in Zaraz po wojnie (1998).
    - Andruszkiewicz, Franciszek, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Andrzejewski, Jerzy, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Berlstein, A., 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Berwińska-Gogolewska, Krystyna, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bochaczewska, Olga, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bochwic, Bolesław, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Borejsza, Jerzy, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Brahmer, Mieczysław, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Breza, Tadeusz and Zofia, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Byrski, Tadeusz, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Caraman Chimay, _____, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Carney, Aubrey, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Chmielnicki, Wincenty and Eugenia, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Chudek, Józef, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Czapski, Józef, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Dickson, Lovat, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Drury, Philip, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Drzewieski, Bernard, 1946-1949 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Elie, Marian, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Girs, Anatol, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Grydzewski, Mieczysław, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Hertz, Paweł, 1946-1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Hiż, Henryk, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Hoffman, Paweł, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Horodyński, Dominik, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Howes Smith, Barbara, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Iwańska, Alicja, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Iwaszkiewicz, Anna, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Iwaszkiewicz, Jarosław, 1947-1950 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Jameson, Margaret Storm, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Janta-Połczyński, Aleksander, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Jastrun, Mieczysław, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Jastrzębiec-Rudnicki, Walery, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Klott-Bujnicka, Anna, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Kocwa, Eugenia, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Kotlicki, Mieczysław, 1947-1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Kowalska, Anna, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Kownacki, Stanisław, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Kridl, Manfred, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Kroński, Tadeusz and Irena, 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Kunatowa, Józefa, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      See also: Miłosz, Aleksander and Miłosz, Andrzej
    - Kuryluk, Karol, 1946-1949, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Leger, Alexis
      See: Saint-John Perse
    - Lipski, Władysław and Elżbieta, 1946-1950 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Łopacińska, Maria, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Matuszewski, Ryszard, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Maynard, Jeanne, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Meysztowicz, Jan, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Micińska, Aniela, 1946-1948, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Micińska, Maria, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Miłosz, Aleksander, 1946-1950 (Box 2, Folder 50-51)
      Includes a letter from Józefa Kunatowa.
    - Miłosz, Andrzej, 1946-1950 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Miłosz, Janina, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Mycielski, Zygmunt, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Niziński, Janusz, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Ordyński, Ryszard, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Ossędowska, Jadwiga, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Płomieński, Jerzy Eugeniusz, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Pruszyński, Ksawery, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Putrament, Jerzy, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Różewicz, Tadeusz, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Rutska, Jadwiga, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Ryńca, Władysław, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Saint-John Perse, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Schiller, Leon, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Słonimski, Antoni, 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Stevenson, Arnold, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Stulgiński, Tadeusz, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Suszkiewicz, Metody, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Taratczakówna, Danuta, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Themerson, Stefan, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Turowiczowa, Anna, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Turowicz, Jerzy, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Unkiewicz, Tadeusz, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Urbanowicz, Bohdan, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Walska, Hanna, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Ważyk, Adam, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Wiercińska, Maria, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Wilson, Gil, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Witkiewiczowa, Jadwiga, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Wittlin, Józef, 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Włodarkiewicz, Janina, 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Wyka, Kazimierz, 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Zabłocki, Mieczysław, 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Zawada, Wojciech, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Zielonko, Jane, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Związek Autorów Kompozytorów i Wydawców (ZAIKS), 1948 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Unidentified, 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Letters to Janina Miłosz, 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 89)
      From: Ludwik Dłuski, Tadeusz Dłuski, Henryka Goszczyńska, Halina Malinowska, Janusz Niziński, unidentified correspondents.
    - Clippings and empty envelopes, 1945-1950 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - General Correspondence
    General Correspondence includes letters from a wide range of professional colleagues, friends, family and fans. Prominent correspondents include Jan Błoński (who took part in the compilation of Miłosz's collected works), Józef Czapski (friend and supporter affiliated with Instytut Literacki), Jerzy Giedroyc (editor of Kultura ), Jan Goślicki (with whom Miłosz corresponded about Stanisław Brzozowski), Zbigniew Herbert (whose poetry Miłosz translated into English), Zygmunt and Zofia Hertz (affiliates of Instytut Literacki who corresponded about the Polish émigré community in France), Konstanty Jeleński, Jerzy Stempowski (essayist and affiliate of Instytut Literacki), Stanisław Vincenz, Aleksander Wat (who recorded his memoir with Miłosz) and Paulina Wat (who worked with Miłosz to publish the work of her husband Aleksander).
    Most fan mail is filed in the general letter files (e.g. "A" general) but particularly substantial files are listed by name.
    Most General Correspondence is incoming. Some files, however, contain outgoing correspondence, including letters to editors of serial publications.
    - 2b (Polish American Academic Quarterly), 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - "A" general (Box 4, Folder 92-98)
    - Aaron, Jonathan, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Academy of American Poets, 1978-1995 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Ad Hoc Committee for Intellectual Freedom, outgoing, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Adamska, Ludmiła, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Akerman, Nordal, 1982-1991 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Aldo Martello editore, 1954-1958 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Alexander, Ronelle, 1986-1994 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1952-1981, undated (Box 5, Folder 106-110)
    - Alvarez, Alfred, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1984-1995 (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - American Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - American Poetry Review, 1974-1988 (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Les Amis De Milosz, 1980-1996 (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - Amnesty International, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Ancevičius, Pranas
      See: Ancewicz, Franciszek
    - Ancewicz, Franciszek, 1953-1958 (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Andrzejewski, Jerzy, incoming and outgoing, 1948-1981 (Box 5, Folder 119)
      See also: Postwar Correspondence.
    - Antemurale, 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Antoniszczak, Richard, 1982-1984
    - Anvil Press Poetry, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Ardis, 1976-1980 (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Arski, Stefan, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Atheneum, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Atlanta Committee for the Olympic Games, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Atlantic Monthly, 1957-1964 (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Augustiniene, Biruta, 1991-1995 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Ault, Donald, 1976-1987 (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - "Ba-Bl" general (Box 6, Folder 129-136)
    - "Bo-By" general (Box 7, Folder 137-143)
    - Baars-Jelgersma, Greta, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - Babinski, Pauline Prus, 1989-1994 (Box 7, Folder 145)
    - Banac, Ivo, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - Banaszak, Antoni, 1961-1986 (Box 7, Folder 147)
    - Barańczak, Stanisław, 1981-1996 (Box 8, Folder 148-150)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      Portions available on microfilm.
    - Bard College, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 151)
    - Basic Books, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 152)
    - Baterowicz, Marek, 1979-1997 (Box 8, Folder 153)
    - Bazilewski, Andrei, 1990-1994 (Box 8, Folder 154)
    - Beauvois, Daniel, 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 155)
    - Bednarczyk, Czesław and Krystyna, 1965-1970 (Box 8, Folder 156)